Kareem Hamada Lotfy Emam

<u>Kareemhamada116@gmail.com</u> | +201091604054 | El Minya, El Minya – Egypt | <u>LinkedIn</u>

Summary

A fresh graduate holds a bachelor's degree in Economics with an excellent academic record, interested in the field of banking and Economic scientific research, I'm trying to enhance my professional skills, capabilities and knowledge in an organization which recognizes the value of hard work and trusts me with responsibilities and challenges.

Education

College of Economics and Political Science | Beni-Suef University.

Sep 2019 – Jul 2023

Bachelor of Economics.

- Grade: Excellent (A-) (3.74 out of 4 | 93.5%)
- Major: Economics
- Minor: Political Science
- Graduation Project: The role of external financing in achieving sustainable development in Egypt. (Published in the National Democratic Center, https://lnkd.in/d8x4jWK4)
- Graduation Project Grade: Excellent (93%).

Professional Experience

Middle Egypt Electricity Distribution Company | El Minya, Egypt.

Aug 2022 – Sept 2022

- One month training in the accounting department.
- The training was in the general Administration of Audit, the general management of accounts, and the general cost management.

Agricultural Bank of Egypt, Minya Branch | El Minya, Egypt.

Jun 2022 – Jul 2022

- Summer Internship during (Summer 2022), for one month.
- Gained knowledge of core banking activities and their applications at the Agricultural Bank of Egypt. Such as (savings & current Accounts fixed & time deposit loans credit & debit cards agricultural investment products)
- Learned banking procedures and executed daily banking tasks with precision and efficiency. Such as (how to print bank statement how to sell loans and convince a client how to make credit & mezza cards).
- Developed communication and teamwork skills through interactions with the team and clients.
- Participated in the bank's rounds within the financial inclusion initiative.

Enactus New BSU | Bani Sweif, Egypt.

Oct 2021 – May 2022

- Project Management Committee Member (PM).
- Active participation in Enactus, a global non-profit organization dedicated to entrepreneurial action for social impact.
- Led a team working on a project to produce an insecticide for armyworms, engaged in project planning, implementation, and evaluation processes.
- Participated in team meetings and facilitated effective communication among team members.

- One-month online summer internship acquired knowledge in financial inclusion and gained insights into the bank's operations and services.
- Focused on the theme of financial inclusion, gaining a comprehensive understanding of its importance and relevance in the banking sector.
- Developed a solid understanding of CIB Bank's operations, products, and services.
- Participated in virtual training sessions and workshops conducted by industry professionals.

Student Union of College of Economics Political and Science.

Oct 2020 – May 2021

- Scientific Committee Member in my college's Student Union for a duration of two years.
- Assisted in inviting guest speakers, managing event logistics, and ensuring smooth operations.
- Contributed to the evaluation and selection of relevant topics and speakers for events.
- Served as a member of the Scientific Committee, contributing to the organization and coordination of academic events and activities.

skills

Computer Skills:

• Operating systems (Windows), Office suites (Microsoft Office).

Languages Skills:

- Arabic: Native language.
- English: very good (B2) in reading, writing, and speaking.

Specialized Skills:

• Proficient in conducting scientific research, including formulating research questions, designing experiments, collecting, and analyzing data, and drawing conclusions.

Interpersonal Skills:

- Good communication skills.
- Ouick learner.
- The ability to multi-task.
- Ability to quickly adapt to new environments and technologies.

Achievements

• Graduated in the top 5 of Economics section of my College.

Personal Details

- Date of Birth: February 7, 2001
- the military status:

References

Marwa Shehab | Agricultural Bank of Egypt, Minya Branch.

- credit manager
- +20 109 019 3822